(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T14:03:35.740300",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
お疲れ様でした、皆さんこんばんは！
Good evening, everyone!
ホロライブ5期生、桃鈴ねねでーす！
Hololive 5th Generation Momosuzu Nene here!
本日はよろしくね、みんな！
Take care of me today, everyone!
わあ、みんなこんに……こんにねね！
Wow, hello everyone... Konni-nene!
いつもだったらね、ライブといえば曲始まりのイメージがあるんですけど、
Usually, a live stream starts with a song,
今日はですね、挑戦したいことがありまして、
but today, there's something I want to try.
実はですね、今体育館のステージの上にいまーす！
Actually, we are right now on a gymnasium stage!
なんでみんなここに立ってると思う？なんで体育館だ分かる人ー！
Why do you think we're standing here? Who knows why it's a gym?!
すごい。おー、可愛い。当てて、可愛いじゃなくて当ててほしい！
Amazing. Oh, cute. Guess—not cute, I want you to guess!
なんていうんだろ、発表する、なんかプレゼンテーション的なね。
How should I put it, like a presentation of sorts.
でもせっかく3Dライブで体が動くので、今回はなんと、
Since my body moves in 3D live, this time, incredibly,
この後に控えているライブに向けて、今からダンスの振り付けを1曲この場で覚えて、
leading up to the upcoming live, I want to learn the choreography right here,
ライブに向かってみたいと思います！
and head into the live!
題して、ねねの挑戦！
Titled: Nene's Challenge!
20分間で振り覚えて、ライブでパフォーマンス！イエーイ！
Learn the choreo in 20 minutes and perform live! Yay!
というわけで、今からねねが先生にダンスの振り教えてもらって、この後のライブの曲を1曲丸々覚えてパフォーマンスしていきたいと思います！
So, Nene will have a teacher teach her the choreography, and I'll memorize a full song for the upcoming live and perform it!
覚え切って成功するか、間違えてごまかしているのか、みんなにも分かるようにしていきたいと思います！
I want everyone to be able to tell if I memorized it successfully or fumbled through it!
で、今日は早速先生が来てくれてるんですけど、あのマイドン先生っていう…
And today, a teacher has come to see us, 'Maidon-sensei'...
マイドン先生ー！
Maidon-sensei!
おねがーるずのマイドンです、お願いします！
I'm Maidon from Oden Girls, nice to meet you!
イエーイ！おでんガールズっていうグループに所属しているマイドン先生っていうね。
Yay! Maidon-sensei belongs to a group called Oden Girls.
かわいいんだけど今日ちょっとあれだね、宇宙人フォルムが強いね！
She's cute, but today she has a strong alien vibe!
見えてますか？ちょっとね、ちょっとねねの要素が入ってるんだよね。
Can you see? It has a bit of Nene's elements in it.
ほら、ここっぴまいどんとか、後ろにねねのリボンがついてたりとか。
Look, like the carrot Maidon here, and Nene's ribbon on the back.
今日はというわけでこの、ま、オレンジのマイドン先生がねねに、えーダンスを教えてくれます！
Today, this orange Maidon-sensei will teach Nene dancing!
こちらになります！Love Destiny / 堀江由衣さんの「Love Destiny」という曲をやりたいと思います！
The song Nene is challenging today is... Love Destiny by Yui Horie!
これねシスプリっていう、妹がいっぱい出てくるアニメのオープニングなんだけど、知ってますか？
This is the opening to an anime called Sister Princess, do you know it?
ちょっとね、だいぶ前のだからね、覚えやすい。ちなみに振り付けは？
Since it's from a while ago, it's easy to memorize.
大丈夫です！大丈夫？本当に？緊張しますね。
It's fine! Fine? Really? I'm super nervous.
まずはマイドン先生がおて…お手本を見せてくれるらしいです！フルで？フルで！
First, it seems Maidon-sensei will show us an example! In full!
じゃあちょっと見せてもらおうかな。ねねはここにいて見てればいいんだもんね？そうなんだね。オッケー！
Then let's have her show us. Nene just needs to stand here and watch, right?
アイタイ アイアイアイアイアイのに アエナイ アイアイアイアイ
Even though I want to see you, I can't meet you...
今夜は 窓を打つ雨より 激しい嵐に揺れてる
Tonight, the window is shaken more by a raging storm than the rain.
アイエナイ アイアイアイアイから もっと 愛 アイアイ つのるよ
Since I can't meet you, my love grows even stronger.
燃え尽きていても これが最後の真実
Even if it burns out, this is my final truth.
初めての出会いは 平凡だったけれど
Our first meeting was ordinary,
会う度に過去の 誰よりも惹かれてく
but every time we meet, I'm drawn to you more than anyone before.
こんな気持ちの言い訳 うまく言えないけど
I can't quite explain away this feeling,
アイタイ
I want to meet you...
アイアイ アイアイ の に
Even though we want to meet, we can't...
アイアイアイアイ 今夜 は
Tonight...
窓 を 打つ 雨 より
More than the rain hitting the window,
激しい 嵐 に 揺れ てる
We're shaken by a fierce storm.
アエナ イ
We can't meet.
アイアイ アイアイ から もっと 愛
From meeting, even more love...
アイアイ つのる よ
It grows stronger.
燃え尽き て も いい
It's alright even if it burns out,
これ が 最後 の 真実
This is the final truth.
初めて の 出会い は 平凡 だっ た けど
Our first encounter was ordinary, but
会う 度 に 過去 の 誰 より も 惹か れ て く
Every time we meet, I'm drawn to you more than anyone.
こんな 気持ち の 訳 うまく 言え ない けど
The reason for this feeling, I can't quite put into words,
運命 の 恋 と 人 は 呼ぶ の でしょう
People call it a destiny love, right?
ひとみ 閉じ たら ふたり に なれる
When I close my eyes, we can be together,
今 たとえ この 部屋 ひとり で も
Even if I'm alone in this room right now.
it's my only destiny
アイタイ アイアイ アイアイ の に
Even though we want to meet, we can't...
アエナ イ アイアイアイアイ 今夜 は
Tonight we're overwhelmed with feelings,
勝手 に あふれ て く
Overflowing freely.
情感 を 止め られ ない だ から
I can't stop this passion, that's why
アイアイ アイアイ タイ だ けど
I want to meet you, but I can't.
アイアイ アイアイ アエナ イ
It's too late to go back,
もう 戻る は し ない
This is the last of faith.
これ が 最後 の 真実
It becomes painful when you think of someone...
誰か を 思う 時 苦しく なる なんて
Until now, I've been breaking down...
これ まで の 自分 が 次々 に 崩れ て く
An unseen power makes me draw closer.
ポーズ と は 裏腹 巻き込ま れ て ゆく
I can't forget that painful night.
見え ない 力 で 引き寄せ られ て ゆく
It's my last destiny.
ひとみ そらさ ず ふたり に なれた
Even though we want to meet, we can't meet...
あの 夜 の 鼓動 忘れない
Tonight the window is shaken violently
it's my last destiny
More by the raging storm than the rain.
アイタイ アイアイ アイアイ の に
We'll love each other more since we can't meet.
アエナ イ アイアイアイアイ 今夜 は
It's alright even if it burns out,
窓 を 打つ 雨 より 激しい 嵐 に 揺れ てる
This is the last of our faith.
アエナ イ アイアイ アイアイ から もっと 愛
The night I thought about the mysterious him, I cried...
アイアイ つのる よ
It's completely a love song.
燃え尽き て も いい これ が 最後 の 真実
That's why I want to meet you, but I can't.
ねぇ 不思議 彼 を 想っ て 泣ける 夜 が ある って
It's too late to go back,
まるで love song だから
This is the last of faith.
アイタイ アイアイ アイアイ タイ
I want to meet you...
だ けど アイアイ アイアイ アエナ イ
But I can't meet you.
もう 戻る は し ない これ が 最後 の 真実
No turning back now, this is our final truth.
えっと、最初、最初まず曲が流れたら…
Um, first, when the song starts playing...
うんうん、いい感じに乗る。
Yeah, yeah, get into the groove nicely.
いい感じに乗る、オッケー。いい感じに乗る。
Get into the groove nicely, okay. Get into the groove nicely.
そう、いい感じに乗ったら、最初からサビのこの振り付けなんだけど。
Right, once you get into the groove, from the very beginning it's this chorus choreography.
あ、ここはね？これ、8の字にこう手を…書いて。
Ah, right here? You draw a figure-eight with your hands like this.
そうそうそう。で、右から1、2、3、4。
That's right, that's right. Then from the right, 1, 2, 3, 4.
来たら、この左手をこうなぞってく。
When it comes, you trace this left hand like this.
あ、そうそうそうそう！1、2、3、4、ドン、ドン、ドン。いいね。
Ah, exactly, exactly! 1, 2, 3, 4, boom, boom, boom. Nice.
そしたら反対。1、2、3、4。
Then the other side. 1, 2, 3, 4.
そしたらこう、肩からこう、オーラを放つ。
Then, from your shoulder, you release an aura like this.
オーラを放つ。1、2、3、4、ドン、ドン、オーラを放つ。
Release the aura. 1, 2, 3, 4, boom, boom, release the aura.
そうそうそう！最初からやると、1、2、3、4、左手見て…
That's right, that's right! Doing it from the start: 1, 2, 3, 4, look at your left hand...
1, 2, 3, 4, 肩からおーら、
1, 2, 3, 4, shoulders from side to side...
肩からおーら、肩からおーら、
Shoulders from side to side!
ドン、ドン、つった！ドン、ドン、つった！
Thump, thump, step!
足はじゃん、じゃん、た、た、右足よ！
Next, your feet step left and right...
で、右手、左手、脇、脇！
Right and left, elbows out!
右、左、脇、脇！で、ひら、ひら、ひら、ひら！
Right, left, elbows out, and flutter, flutter, flutter!
足はこう右に出して、左に出す！右手左手脇脇、ひらひらひらひら！
Feet out to the right, then left, elbows out, and flutter, flutter, flutter!
そしたら、縦、横、で回る！
Then vertical, horizontal, and spin!
の時にこっち！で、足が、足が、で、ふりふり、ふりふり！
And sway, sway!
縦、横、回る！で、ふりふり、ふりふり！
Vertical, horizontal, spin, and sway, sway!
せーの、だんだん、脇脇、ひらひらひらひら、
1, 2, 3, 4, elbows, elbows, flutter, flutter, flutter, flutter...
縦、横、回る、ふりふり、ふりふり！
Vertical, horizontal, spin, and sway, sway!
ふり、ふり、ふり、ふり、ふり、ふり！
Flutter twice, big flutter, flutter, flutter...
せーの、だんだん、だんだん、左手見て！いー、いー、いー、いー、肩からおーら、
1, 2, 3, 4, left hand...
じゃんじゃん、脇脇、ひらひらひらひら、縦、横、回る、ふりふり！
1, 2, 3, 4, shoulders from side to side...
だんだん、また左手見て！だんだん、肩からおーら！
1, 2, 3, 4, left hand, shoulders from side to side...
右手前に出して、上げて、あ、ここ決めだもんね。そうなの。
Right hand out, raise it, and set it.
きみよりちょっと前か。だ、だ、だ、で、これ裏側。あ、そうそうそう。
1, 2, 3, 4, from the back...
手を見せて、やっぱ見せない！見せて、見せない！手を見せて、やっぱ見せない！
Show your hands, and never hide them!
右手、左手、で、しんじつ、てはパー、グー、グー、パー！
Right hand, left hand, 1, 2, 3, 4, rock, paper, scissors, scissors, rock...
結局、手は見せる！あ、オッケー、見せる！パー、グー、グー、パー！
So you do show your hands!
ちょっと逆に流してみるか？今日、物理的に流せるようにね、用意してくれてるんで。
Let's try flowing through it from the reverse.
じゃあ最初いい感じに乗る？あ、いい感じに乗る？で、サビだもんね。あ、そうそう、せーの、左手、
1, 2, 3, 4, left hand...
だんだん、だんだん、肩からおーら、だんだん、きらきらきらきら、縦、横、
1, 2, 3, 4, shoulders from side to side, sparkle, sparkle...
だんだん、だんだん、反対、肩からおーら、手で見せて、やっぱ見せない！右手、左手、だ、
1, 2, 3, 4, shoulders from side to side, right hand, left hand, never show...
しんじつ、あ、そうそう、最後は、ぱ、ここで一緒に、あ、そうそう、足を、そうそうそう、ぴたっ。
Shinjitsu (Truth), and finally, put your feet together...
おー、あと15分しかないよ。あった？とりあえず踊った。
Only 15 minutes left!
今サビができたね。そしたらもう、これやったら、あの、ねねさん得意のアイドルステップね。
Now that the chorus is done, let's do the idol steps!
かわいいく、かわいいく4回やったら、えめろ、こちに、だん。あ、ここ簡単なとき、あ、そうそう、簡単簡単。4歩、4歩いきます。
Cute, cute, 4 times, then el mero to the side...
だん、だん、だん、だん、3歩目から手を腰に。あ、そうそうそう。
1, 2, 3, 4, and 3 steps in, hands on waist...
そしたら手、上げて、開いて、だん。あ、そうそうそう。
Then raise your hands and open up!
え、回転、がらがら、回転、がらがら、オープン、オープン！4歩出てね。あ、そうそうそう。1、2、3、4、回転！
Rotation, rotation, open, open, 1, 2, 3, 4, rotation...
ガラガラ オープン
Garagara, open!
ツンチャ ツンチャ
Tsun-cha, tsun-cha...
右足 あ、そうそう右足
Right foot. Ah, right, right, right foot.
ツンチャ ツンチャ タッタ タッタ
Tsun-cha, tsun-cha, ta-tta ta-tta.
2回抜き振って あと胸
Then swing it out twice... and chest.
ツンチャ ツンチャ タッタ タッタ
Tsun-cha, tsun-cha, ta-tta ta-tta.
内 外 ジャンプ ジャンプ
In, out, jump, jump!
そう、今度手離して
Right, now release your hands,
内 外 ジャンプ ジャンプ
in, out, jump, jump!
悩む時
When you're hesitating—
ツンツン 2回やったら 蹴る 蹴る
Tsun-tsun, do it twice, then kick, kick!
で戻る タンダン でガッツだぜ
Then return, dan-dan, and give it your all!
ガッツだぜ
Give it your all!
戻って
Return,
ガッツだぜってやったら その手そのまま前
and when you say 'give it your all,' keep that hand in front.
右手 左手 で、ぐるーっと
Right hand, left hand, and spin all around—
回して ぐるーっと
spin it all around!
1回目 2回目 終わる時に右足出す
The first time, second time, put out your right foot when ending.
そう、で、ほっ そう
Right, and... hop, right!
次に入る ね、じゃあじゃあじゃあ
Entering the next part. Yeah, yeah, yeah...
回転ガラガラ オープン
Spinning, garagara, open!
ツンチャ ツンチャ ツンチャ ツンチャ
Tsun-cha, tsun-cha, tsun-cha, tsun-cha...
内 外 と、内 外 と
In and out, in and out...
ツン ツン 蹴る タンダン
Tsun, tsun, kick, ta-dan!
ガッツだぜ その手 そのまま
Give it your all, keep those hands as they are.
で、タントン ダントン タントン
And, tan-ton, dan-ton, tan-ton...
ここがちょっと早い タッタ
Here is a little fast, ta-tta.
さあ、ほ、ははは 右メロ
Now, ho, haha, right melody—
チャチャチャチャチャチャ チャチャチャチャチャチャ
Cha-cha-cha-cha-cha-cha...
左手 右手 開いて 開いて 1つ 1つ
Left hand, right hand, open, open, one by one.
で、これ 8回 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
And this 8 times: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
右手大きく回して ドゥンドゥン
Swing your right hand wide, dun-dun!
足はね戻すね ドゥンドゥンドゥン
Return your feet, dun-dun-dun.
タンダン タッ タッ で、パー
Tan-dan, ta-ta, and... pose!
そしたらまたサビ行く
Then go to the chorus again.
おっけー そうそう Bメロは
Okay, yeah yeah, the B-melody is...
ターン ターンツンチャ タッタタッタ...
Tan, tan-tsun-cha, ta-tta ta-tta...
左手 右手 開いて 両手で
Left hand, right hand, open with both hands.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 ターン
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, tan!
それはあの 改札通る感じ
That feels like going through the ticket gate.
スイカ スイカ、パスモでも可
Suica, Suica, PASMO is fine too.
ピ ツー ツッチャ ダー
Pi, tsu, tsucca, da!
オッケー オッケーしょ じゃあ曲でやろう
Okay, okay, then let's do it with the song.
え、Aメロ Aメロから行こう
Uh, A-melody, let's start from A-melody.
最後の一滴まで
To the very last drop,
アイドルステップ
idol step...
つんつん つんつん つんつんつん
tsun-tsun, tsun-tsun, tsun-tsun-tsun...
右に 左に で腰
To the right, to the left, and the waist.
回転ガラガラ オープン
Spinning, garagara, open!
ツンチャ ツンチャ ツンチャ ツンチャ
Tsun-cha, tsun-cha, tsun-cha, tsun-cha...
内外 ジャンプ
In-out, jump!
ツンツン 蹴る 戻る ガッツだぜ
Tsun-tsun, kick, return, give it your all!
ダントン ダントン くるー
Tan-ton, dan-ton, spin around...
右足出すよ タッタタッタタッタ...
Put out your right foot, ta-tta ta-tta...
左手 両手 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
Left hand, both hands, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
ぴっつー たったった
Pi-tsu, ta-ta-ta...
サビ 8の字ダンス
Chorus: 8-figure dance!
あ、フラフラフラ フラフラフラ
Ah, fluttering, fluttering...
タッピ 横向こう
Tap, turn sideways.
左手 反対 がったからおーら
Left hand, opposite, gattakara ohra...
いいこと起こそう 右手と親指と...
Let's make good things happen, right hand and thumb...
アイドルステップ 繰り返し
Idol step, repeat.
今度胸に 苦しくなってね
Now to the chest, it gets painful...
また回転ガラガラ オープン
And spinning, garagara, open again!
ちょっと待って
Wait a minute.
ここも一緒
This part is the same too.
ターン、ターン、タタタッって
Turn, turn, ta-ta-ta...
ピキがちょっとクルクルする
My piki spins a little bit.
クルクル
Spin, spin.
え、ガチダンス？え？
Eh, serious dance? Eh?
ターン、ターン、タタタッ
Turn, turn, ta-ta-ta...
クルクル、もう回、クルクル、見逃し
Spin, spin, once more, spin, missed it.
ほい、ほい
Hoi, hoi!
正解
Correct!
ターン、ターン、い、に、さん、し
Turn, turn, one, two, three, four...
左手から、うん、うん
From the left hand, yeah, yeah.
ほい、ほい
Hoi, hoi!
あ、もうできるはここ。12345678
Ah, I can do this part. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
ピーン、とんとん、ターン
Pin, ton-ton, turn.
あ、またサビだ。
Ah, chorus again.
あ、最高！
Ah, awesome!
問題はサビの好きだな。
The real challenge is after the chorus.
ターン、ターン、脇脇、ヒーラヒーラヒラ
Turn, turn, waki-waki, heela-heela-hira...
縦、横、うーん
Vertical, horizontal, hmm...
よしよしよし
Good, good, good!
左手、ターン、ターン、肩からオラ
Left hand, turn, turn, from the shoulder, ora!
きのう、今日1度目出ていな...
Yesterday, coming out for the first time today...
ちゃんと、え、でもここまで来たよ。よしよし、あ、リズムステップだ。
Seriously? Eh, but we've made it this far. Good, good. Ah, it's rhythm steps.
タン、タン
Tan, tan.
じゃあでもこっからだったんだもんな。
Well, but it was from here, wasn't it?
ねえ、実はね、ここ野...
Hey, actually, here...
シーメロ、シーメロはね、自由になってるので
C-melody, the C-melody is free, so...
あ、ラッキー！
Ah, lucky!
ねえ、さあ、だから、
Hey, so...
あのねねさんの自由にこう、アドリブで、あ、オッケー、踊ってもらいます。
freely improvise and dance to it.
ここワンフレーズ全部ね。あ、そう、間奏前まで。あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー。
This whole one phrase. Ah, right, up until before the interlude. Ah, okay, okay, okay.
フリー、フリーでやってもらって。で、次だよね？問題はね。
Do it freely. And then next, right? The problem is...
間奏のとこ、間奏をやってみよっか。はい。
The interlude part. Let's try the interlude. Okay.
で、間奏、間奏はトントン、トントン。さ、
So the interlude is ton-ton, ton-ton. Now,
右手、左手。そしたら、トントンクロス。
Right hand, left hand. Then, ton-ton cross.
そうそうそう。タンダンダンダン、クロス。やったら、巻いて、巻いて、腹う。
That's right, that's right. Tan-tan-tan-tan, cross. When you do that, wind, wind, strike the belly.
ツンじゃ、ツンじゃ、クロス、巻いて、腹う。そうそうそう。そっから
Tsun-ja, tsun-ja, cross, wind, strike the belly. That's right. From there...
グーーン！
Guuuun!
急な横キャ...
Sudden side movement...
右手、左手クロス、巻いて、腹ってうぇーーい！
Right hand, left hand cross, wind, strike the belly and weeee!
1、2、3、4、うん、うん。
1, 2, 3, 4, yep, yep.
あ、そうそうそう。そしたら、ちょっとドキナサイってこうやって、ドキナサイ、あ、そうそう。
Ah, right, right. Then, "step aside" like this, step aside, ah, right.
で、あのね、後ろ回り？いつもウチがやってる。タダダ、タダダ...
And, you know, backward spin? What we usually do. Tada-da, tada-da...
あ、そうそうそう。ここのお楽しみがあるから。そしたらもうサビだよ？あーーい！
Ah, right, right. Because there's this fun part here. Then it's the chorus already? Aaa-i!
もう一回感想、あ、一緒一緒一緒。
Interlude again. Ah, together, together, together.
おっけ。感想もう一回やると。ツンじゃ、ツンじゃ、クロス、巻いて腹ってうぇーーい！
Okay. Doing the interlude again. Tsun-ja, tsun-ja, cross, wind, strike the belly and weeee!
トントン、タンダ、で、どいてって。
Ton-ton, tan-da, and "step aside".
どいてって。あ、そうそう。で、ダダ、ダダ、ダダ...
"Step aside". Ah, right, right. And dada, dada, dada...
で、ここい。急に、ちょっと音聞いてみようか。
And, here. Suddenly, let's listen to the music for a moment.
ああ、大事、大事。大事だよね。
Ah, important, important. It's important, right?
ま、ここはね、狂ってるみたいっていって
Well, here, it's like "we're going crazy,"
おーーい！
Oooo-i!
あ、これやる？やるやる。
Ah, do we do this? Do it, do it.
ここまで自由。あ、ここまでオッケー。
Free until here. Ah, okay up to here.
はい、せーの！ツンじゃ、ツンじゃ、タンダ、ツンじゃ、うぇーーい！
Ready, go! Tsun-ja, tsun-ja, tan-da, tsun-ja, weeee!
はい、トントン、タンダ、ダダダダダダダダダ...
Yep, ton-ton, tan-da, dadadadadadada...
ピカチュウ！うーー、なるほど！さあ！
Pikachu! Oooo, I see! Now!
いいじゃん。
That's pretty good.
そしたら、なんと最後は、この脇脇がない！えーー！？もうすぐ手そうみせる。
Then, surprisingly, at the end, there's no waki-waki! Eeeee?! Show your hands soon.
あ、そうそうそう。歌詞的にね、そうそうそう。
Ah, right, right. Lyrically speaking, right, right.
ジャンジャンジャンジャン、ちゃらららら。
Chan chan chan chan, charararara.
反対やって、肩からオーラやったら、手そう見せる。
Do the opposite, and once you do the aura from the shoulder, show your hands.
やばみせしない。
Don't show the yaba-mise.
で、ツンじゃ、ツンじゃ、タンダ。で、もう最後。
And tsun-ja, tsun-ja, tan-da. And then the very end.
ダダダダダター！あーー！
Dadadadadata! Aaaah!
で、アイドルステップして。
And do the idol step.
はい、いい感じに乗る。いい感じに乗る、オッケー。
Yep, ride the beat nicely. Ride the beat nicely, okay.
いい感じに乗る。2回ずつ！2回ずついい感じに、
Ride nicely. Twice each! Twice each, nice and nicely...
え、手を下からファーーン！
Eh, hands from below, faaaan!
で、こういい感じに回って、いい感じに回って、で、あの意味ありげにポーズ。オッケー！
And spin nicely, spin nicely, and then pose with deep meaning. Okay!
大丈夫かな？Love Destinyも込みでね？あ、そうそうそう。オッケーオッケーオッケーオッケー。
Will it be okay? Including Love Destiny too? Ah, right, right, right. Okay, okay, okay, okay.
え、もう、もう終わった。あ、そこやりたいな。
Eh, already, already finished. Ah, I want to do that part.
あの、ここの
Um, this part...
わきわきのとこ サビの
The waki-waki part, in the chorus...
そう心配ね。サビの? そうサビの。
Yeah, I'm worried. The chorus? Yeah, the chorus.
あ、トントン わきわき 右
Ah, ton-ton, waki-waki, right,
左 わきわき
left, waki-waki...
ひら ひら ひら ひら
hira, hira, hira, hira...
で縦 横 で回る
then vertical, horizontal, spin around...
で ふりふり ふりふり ふりふり
and furi-furi, furi-furi, furi-furi...
あ、そうそうそうそう
Ah, right, right, right!
ああ、もう1回、もう1回。
Ah, once more, once more!
ちゃん、ちゃん、ちゃん、ちゃん、ちゃかちゃか
Chan, chan, chan, chan, chaka-chaka...
やばい、ここ増やせない。
Oh no, I can't keep up here!
やばい。ちゃん、ちゃん、ちゃん 肩からおろす
Oh no. Chan, chan, lower from shoulders...
ちゃん、ひら、ひら、ひら、ひら
chan, hira, hira, hira, hira...
縦、横、回る
vertical, horizontal, spin...
あ、そうそうそうそう！
Ah, right, right, right, right!
これを歌いながらやるってことですか？ そうです。
"You mean doing this while singing?" "That's right."
マジ？ ひく口に出して必死なのに。
Seriously? I'm already struggling just to voice it!
でもほんまマイドン先生、ね、前でね、できないところで なんてやってくれるもんね。
But Maidon-sensei, you're right up front doing the impossible...
なんて、やってくれるもんね。 やってないよ！
"...and doing it so easily!" "I am not!"
見てるよ。
I'm watching you!
無理無理無理無理！
No way, no way, no way!
ちょ待って、あと5分。あと5分あります。
Wait, 5 minutes left. We have 5 more minutes.
あ、3分。ちょっと行こう。
Ah, 3 minutes. Let's go.
ええと、2番、2番から行こう。
Uh, let's start from the 2nd verse.
2番から行こう。
Let's start from the 2nd verse.
通しでやれたらいい。はい。
It'd be great if we could do it all the way through. Yes.
ふん、ふん、ふん、ふん
Hum, hum, hum, hum...
誰かを思う時
When thinking of someone...
切ねえ、そう
It's painful, yeah.
回転グルグル
Spinning around and around...
ここまで、縦、横、回る
Up to here, vertical, horizontal, spin...
はい、はい、はい、ズレた
Yes, yes, yes, out of sync!
はい、いいよ、はい、くるくるくるくる
Yeah, good, yeah, spin, spin, spin, spin...
はい、ドン、ドン、タン、タン
Yes, ton, ton, tan, tan...
ガッツだぜ、ガッツだぜ
You've got guts, you've got guts!
はい、て、ドン、ドン、きゅー
Yes, te, ton, ton, cue...
首足出す？ ほい、はい
Stick out neck and feet? Hoi, yes!
ひら、ひら、ひら、ひら、反対、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ
Hira, hira, hira, opposite, cha, cha, cha, cha...
左手、右手、回して、はい、はい
Left hand, right hand, spin, yes, yes...
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、はい、はい、ぴった
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, yes, yes, spot on!
ああ、ぴー忘れちゃった！
Ah, I forgot the "pi"!
反対、回転からおら
Opposite, from the spin, ora!
逆になっちゃう！
It's backwards!
ひら、ひら、ひら、ひら、縦、横、回る
Hira, hira, hira, hira, vertical, horizontal, spin...
はい、足やばい！足やばい！
Yes, my legs are crazy! My legs are crazy!
手相見せて、手相、あ、やっぱ見せない
Show me your palm, palm... ah, I won't show it.
真実、ふん、ふん、ふん
Truth, hum, hum, hum...
アイドルステップ、で、ふりでね、そうそう、ふり
Idol step, and with a swing, yeah, yeah, swing...
ごまかすパートねの
The part where we fake it...
みんな見ようね、とこ、見る、とこ
Everyone look here, this part, looking part...
愛を、見てる、みんな
Looking at love, everyone...
せーの、はい、はい、はい、はい、うえーい
Ready, go, yes, yes, yes, yes, ugh-ei...
はい、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ、ちゃ
Yes, cha, cha, cha, cha, cha, cha, cha...
はい、はい、あら、逆になっちゃう
Yes, yes, oh, it's backwards!
あれ、えっと、えっと、なんだからおら、ふり
Huh, um, from what, ora, swing...
すみません、あははは
Excuse me, ahahaha!
真実、あ、ここ決まればね
Truth, ah, if we nail this part...
まるできできた雰囲気
It'll look like we totally nailed it!
で、2回ずついい感じにのるよ、いいよ
And ride it nicely two times each, good, good...
はい、はい、はい、でいい感じに回って、いい感じに回って
Yes, yes, yes, then spin nicely, spin nicely...
はい、意味ありげにとどめ
Yes, finishing with a meaningful pose...
大好きだもんね、意味ありげ、いいじゃん、いいじゃん
We love it, right? Meaningful, looks good, looks good!
5分、あ、終わったもう！
5 minutes... ah, it's already over!
と言うわけで、終了の時間だそうだ。
And with that, it seems time is up.
ちょっとお水飲みたい。
I want to drink some water.
お水、お水。ありがとうね。
Water, water. Thank you.
あ、美味しるなってしまった！
Ah, it turned out delicious!
よしよしよしよし、どう？どう？どう？どう？
Good, good, good, how is it? How is it?
いや、割りとありだよね。
Well, it's totally doable.
え、全然いける。ちょっと割りとごまかせる？
Eh, totally fine. Can we fudge it a bit?
調子いいな、なんか。
We're on a roll today, somehow.
全然いける。あ、全然いける。
Totally fine. Ah, totally fine.
本当に、いけるいける。ごまかせ、ごまかせ。
Really, we got this. Fake it, fake it.
見たくね？ あ、違う、違わせ。
Want to see? Ah, no, let me rephrase.
ちょっと軽くね、軽くやって もらうから。見たくね？
Let's have you do it lightly. Want to see?
ああ！
Ah!
まあまあ、どうですか、みんな的に？
Well, how is it, from everyone's perspective?
ごまかせる、いけるいける！
Can we fudge it? We can totally do it!
ごまかせる、ごまかしていこう！
Let's fudge it and push through!
ま、でもね、この曲実は、セトリ的に ちょっと真ん中のほうに持ってき たくて。
Actually, we wanted this song more towards the middle.
一旦、温めます、この曲。温めようか、じゃあ。
First, we'll warm up with this song. Let's warm up, then.
自然の体温がいまもぽかぽかなので、このままね、ライブ改造に行って
Our body temperature is cozy, so going straight into live mode...
ねの、セトリがね、始まりますので、今からステージに飛ぶんだけど
Neno's setlist is starting, so we'll fly to the stage now,
マイドン先生はここで一旦お別れなんだけど、一緒に飛んでもらったら
and Maidon-sensei will part ways here, but if you fly with us...
ねのが...
Neno will...
まいどん先生まで飛ばしちゃいけ？
Shall I fast-forward to maido-sensei?
あ、いいですか？
Ah, is that okay?
うん、行くよ！
Yeah, let's go.
せーの、わっ！
Ready, go!
うわーっ！
Whew!
まいどん先生は無事にね、ねねが
Maido-sensei, successfully...
飛ばしておきました！
よしよしよしよしよし！
まいどん先生を今帰宅させたんで
Maido-sensei has been sent home now,
こっからはですね、ねねのライブパートをやっていきたいと思います！
so from here on, I'd like to do the live performance part!
ちょっとね、
Let's, um...
もう一回だけお水飲んで、
Drink some more water first.
よし。
Okay.
息を整えたら
Get my breath back, then...
ライブパートに入っていきたいと思います！
live performance!
というわけで、えー桃鈴ねね誕生日2023
So, Momosuzu Nene's birthday 2023,
毎日ねねかの誕生日ライブ！スタート！
Everyday is Nene's Birthday Live, start!
hand in hand, let's go party night!
ココロ踊る 止められないの
The emotion of my heart will not stop.
泣いて 笑って
Laughing and crying,
きみとの記憶
with you in my memories,
ずーっと忘れない
I will never forget it.
本当の自分はどこにいるとか
Finding my real self,
大人になるって大変で
or becoming an adult is hard,
今は忘れてもいいかな
so it's okay to forget about the present,
夜が待っているから
because the night is waiting.
心を弾ませ
When we can let our hearts bounce,
会える時をはしゃぎまわれば
if we walk around cheerfully...
伝えたい想いにまで 気付いてしまいそうで
I might notice these feelings I want to convey to you.
過去と未来 恐れていても
Even if we fear the past and the future,
からっぽのままだ動けない
we cannot move if we stay empty.
楽しめば It's all right!
If we enjoy it, it's all right!
はじめよう
Let's begin!
ヤなこと全部忘れて きみと一緒に踊り明かせば
If I dance all night with you and forget everything unpleasant,
もっと素敵な自分になれる そんな気がするの
I have the feeling that I can become a more wonderful self.
終わらない ゴールデンタイム
An endless golden time,
ぎゅっと近づき きみとの距離は
closely reducing the distance between us.
すぐず離れず 回り道でも 大切にしたい
Even if we deviate and separate, I want to treasure it.
夢見る自分はどこにいるとか
Finding the self I saw in my dreams,
未来なんてわからない
or not knowing anything about the future,
あるがままで生きたいの！
I want to live just as I am!
夜は待ってくれないから
Because the night won't wait anymore.
好きと嫌い 恐れていても
Even if we fear loving and hating,
心はいま嘘をつけない
our hearts now tell no lies.
伝えなきゃ Never give up!
I have to convey them, never give up!
はじめよう
Let's begin!
ヤなこと全部忘れて 恥ずかしさのかなぐり捨てたら
If I dance all night with you and get rid of my shame,
もっと素敵な自分になれる そんな気がするの
I have the feeling that I can become a more wonderful self.
始まりは ゴールデンタイム
The beginning is the golden time.
あのとき紡ぎ合った言葉
The words that we intertwined at that time,
それはたしかに 永遠に見えた
they truly looked like they would last forever.
夢のつづきね
The continuation of the dream...
胸張って歩こう
I will walk holding my heart high.
はじめよう
Let's begin!
目と目が合う瞬間
The moment we met face to face,
楽しいほど切なくなって
it was as fun as it was painful.
ぼおっとしてたら 夜明けはすぐに追いかけてくるよ
If we daydream, dawn will chase us immediately.
hand in hand, let's go party night!
ココロ踊る 止められないの
The emotion of my heart will not stop.
泣いて 笑って
Laughing and crying,
きみとの記憶
with you in my memories,
ずーっと忘れない
I will never forget it.
これからのことも これまでのことも
The things from now on, and the things up to now,
少しずつ ちゃんとすべてを受れ入れられる
little by little, I can accept them all perfectly.
信じられる きみがいるなら
I will believe it if I am with you.
このゴールデンタイムね、なんかまあまあ結構前の曲なんですけどね
This Golden Time is a pretty old song, you know,
この曲ねすごいなんかYouTube、何で聞いたのかな、なんかアニメとかそういうのかなで聞いて耳に残ってて今回はやろうかなと思ってこの曲を選んでみました！
I heard it on YouTube or maybe in an anime somewhere, and it stayed in my head, so I chose it for today!
え、そして今日ちょっと遅くなってしまったんですけど
And well, today it ended up being a bit late,
無事ねの生誕祭を迎えることができました！いぇーい！
but we were able to safely celebrate Nene's birthday! Yay!
みんな改めてありがとう！はーい！
Thank you all once again! Yay!
え、今回お誕生日ということで、お花をね、ステージのお花とかを前回のさ、2周年のときよりもいっぱいいっぱい咲かせてもらいました！
Also, since it's my birthday, we have way more flowers on stage than during our 2nd anniversary!
見てなんか顔がついてて花がいっぱい揺れててしょ、かわいい！キュートキュート！なんとね、床にもね、あの、
Look, they have faces and sway around, so cute! And even on the floor,
花びらが散ってると思うんですけどなんか春っぽい感じでねライブ中も花びら舞っちゃったりなんかして
there are fallen petals, giving it a spring-like feel with petals dancing during the live!
いい雰囲気が出ております。
It's creating such a nice atmosphere.
今回はいつものあのスタジオじゃなくてね、今回違うところなので、あの、いっぱいいっぱいね、人がいてもちょっと緊張するんですけど、頑張っていきたいと思います！
This time we're not in the usual studio, so having so many people around makes me a bit nervous, but I'll do my best!
そして今回もロゴを作っていただきました！ももすずねね生誕ライブ2023 毎日誰かの誕生日、というわけで、
And they made a logo for us this time too! 'Momosuzu Nene Birthday Live 2023: Someone's Birthday Every Day', so,
今日のハッシュタグはですね、えー、#ももすずねね誕生日2023、こちらでたくさんつぶやいていただければと思います！
today's hashtag is #MomosuzuNeneBirthday2023. I hope you'll tweet a lot using this!
みんなよろしくね！がんばれ…あ、すげえって、そうだよね、すごいよね、ステージ！
Thank you everyone! Do your best... Ah, 'amazing', that's right, the stage is amazing!
えー、次なんですけれども、ちょっとねのね、休憩を挟みつつ、え、ゲストパートに行きたいなと思っておりますので、今から過去のねねにパスをしていきたいと思います！
Well, next, while taking a short break, I'd like to move on to the guest segment, so I'll pass it over to past Nene now!
というわけでみんなゲストパー…あ、パートじゃない、ゲストパートを、レッツラゴー！
With that everyone, let's get the guest par... ah, not part, let's go to the guest segment!
はい、ということでここからはゲストパートに入っていくんですけど、
Right, so from here we're entering the guest segment,
え、ちょっとまだ誰が来るかね、わかんない！
and well, we still don't know who's coming!
え、誰が来ると思うみんな？
Who do you think is coming, everyone?
いや誰が、誰が来るんだろうな！いやみんなすっごいドキドキしてると思うんですけど、ゲストね、3人来てくれて、あの一緒にね今から歌って踊ってくれますので、
I wonder who's coming! I'm sure you're all super excited, three guests are coming to sing and dance with us starting now,
いやー本当誰が来るかね、本当に全然わかんない。
man, I really don't know who's coming at all.
全然わかんないんだけど、え、運動して、あ、運動して、ゲスト来てくれるんでみんなすごいね、誰が来るかな？
I really have no idea, but um, exercising, ah, exercising, since the guests are coming, everyone is wondering who it'll be?
誰が来るかなっていうワクワクしてると思うんですけど、あ、えー、じゃあ行っちゃいますか？
You're probably all excited wondering who's coming, ah, well, shall we go then?
とと、始めちゃいますか？
Wait, shall we start?
え、そう、じゃあゲストじゃ…あれ？本当に？え、じゃあちょっとね、ね、たち…え？ゲストしてまだ来てないけど、誰やろ、つくわ。
Eh, right, then guest... Huh? Really? Well then, wait... Eh? As guests they haven't arrived yet, who could it be?
え、誰よ？俺よ！？
Eh, who is it? Me!y?
あんじゃわしら、んじゃ、うちら、うちら、位置を、位置を付いてみる？立ち位置に、ねえねえ、自分たちの足跡は、
Then us, shall we try taking our positions? On our spots, hey, our footprints,
やればできるかもしれない。おお！
maybe we can do it if we try. Oh!
光る風を追い越したら
After I've passed the glittering wind,
君にきっと逢えるね
I will surely meet you.
新しい輝き
A new brilliance,
HAPPY READY GO!!
目覚めたばかりの ときめき弾けそう
Just waking up, an excitement about to burst,
胸ポケットに詰めて 空を見上げた
stuffed in my chest pocket, I looked up at the sky.
前髪の行方を 鏡とにらめっこ
Playing a staring game with the mirror about my bangs,
オリジナル笑顔で 駆け抜けたいよ
I want to run through with an original smile.
一秒ごとドキドキ 色付く日々が
Every second throbbing, these colorful days
未来地図になる 高鳴る鼓動
become a map for the future, a racing heartbeat.
光る風を追い越したら
After I've passed the glittering wind,
何が待っているのかな
I wonder what's waiting for me there.
雨降でも平気 虹になるよ
I don't mind rain for it turns into a rainbow.
カラフル☆ハッピー☆マテリアルGO!!
Colorful Happy Material GO!!
君にきっと逢えるね
I will surely meet you,
小さな勇気を 咲かせよう
let's make our tiny courage bloom.
光る風を追い越したら
After I've passed the glittering wind,
何が待っているのかな
I wonder what's waiting for me there.
雨降でも平気 虹になるよ
I don't mind rain for it turns into a rainbow.
カラフル☆ハッピー☆マテリアルGO!!
Colorful Happy Material GO!!
君にきっと逢えるね
I will surely meet you,
小さな勇気を 咲かせよう
let's make our tiny courage bloom.
流行もStudyも
Fashion and study,
要点チェックでOK
key point check is OK!
標的を確認
Confirming the target,
スピード勝負
a speed battle.
喉ごし爽やかな
Refreshing to the throat,
特別な予感が
a special premonition
この胸溢れてく
overflows from this chest,
加速してくよ
accelerating away!
涙隠した笑顔 君は気付いてるね
You notice the smile hiding my tears, don't you?
恋しよ!夢見よ!私らしく
Fall in love! Dream! True to myself!
願いの先へJumpしたら 受け止めてくれるかな?
If I jump beyond my wish, will you catch me?
悩む前にできることをしよう
Let's do what we can before worrying!
カラフル☆ハッピー☆マテリアルGO!!
Colorful☆Happy☆Material GO!!
お揃いのきらめき
Matching sparkle,
君に届けたい
I want to deliver to you,
HAPPY READY GO!!
光る風を追い越したら
If we outrun the shining wind,
何が待っているのかな
what could be waiting for us?
雨降りでも平気 虹になるよ
Even in the rain it's fine, it becomes a rainbow.
カラフル☆ハッピー☆マテリアルGO!!
Colorful☆Happy☆Material GO!!
君にきっと逢えるね
I'll surely meet you there.
小さな勇気を咲かせよう
Let's make a small courage bloom.
君に届けたい
I want to deliver it to you,
HAPPY READY GO!!
ねね お誕生日 おめでとう！
Nene, happy birthday!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
今日はねぽらぼの皆さん来ていただいて
Thank you all from NePoLaBo for coming today,
ありがとうございます!
thank you so much!
うちらが来たんだから別にいいじゃん
We came here, so it's totally fine!
おめでとうございます!
Happy birthday!
3人のゲストって誰だったの?
Who were the three guests?
みんなだったかも!
It might have been everyone!
何だったんだって!何だったのさっきのは!
What was that all about! What was that just now!
あれ最近ちょっと筋トレしてたから
Well, I've been doing a bit of muscle training lately,
ステージ上でもやんだ
so I did it on stage too.
やっぱねいつでもどこでも筋トレしてこないと
You've gotta do muscle training anytime, anywhere.
その自由な感じのさ、スクショタイムが欲しいって思うからさ、みんな自由にしていって写真撮ってもらおう!
We want a free screenshot time, so let's all pose freely and take photos!
難易度高いよそれ
That difficulty level is high!
5、4、3、2、1！
5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
よかったのこんなので
Was it really okay to do this?
それじゃあ帰って帰って帰って！
Well then, go home, go home, go home!
そんな時間なくてよ
We don't have that kind of time!
しんみりすんな！
Don't get all sentimental!
一本締め！
Let's do a single clap!
というわけでご覧いただきました！ねぽらぼの皆に来ていただきました！
And with that, thank you for watching! Everyone from NePoLaBo came to join us!
みんな自由ですごく良かったでしょ？
It was so free and great, right?
選曲もねねね、めっっちゃナイスな感じだったんじゃないかなあ、と
And I think Nene's song choice was super nice, don't you?
では、ねねですパートのね、休憩もできたので、次の曲に行きたいと思います！
Well, since we had a little break during Nene's part, I'd like to move on to the next song!
よし、じゃあちょっと身なり直して、それでは聞いてください、ユキドキ
Alright, let me tidy up a bit, so please listen to "Yukidoki".
陽の満ちるこの部屋
In this sunlit room
そっとトキを待つよ
waiting softly for the moment.
気づけば俯瞰で
Before I knew it, looking
眺めてる箱
down at the box from above,
同じ目線は無く
with no one sharing my perspective.
いつしか心は白色不透明
Eventually my heart became white and opaque,
雪に落ちた光も散る
and the light that fell into the snow scattered.
雲からこぼれる冷たい雨
Cold rain spilling from the clouds,
目を晴らすのは遠い春風だけ
and only a distant spring breeze clears my eyes.
アザレアを咲かせて 暖かい庭まで
Make azaleas bloom, until the warm garden,
連れ出して 連れ出して なんてね
take me away, take me away... just kidding.
幸せだけ描いた お伽話なんてない
There's no fairy tale drawn with only happiness,
わかってる わかってる それでもね そこへ行きたいの
I know, I know, but still, I want to go there.
難しい数式 誰も頼らず
Relying on no one for difficult formulas,
解いて明かしてきた
I've solved and brought them to light.
当たり前だって思っていたから 何も疑っていなかったけど
I thought it was natural, so I never doubted anything, but
今季節が終わろうとしても
Even as this season is about to end,
ついてくるのは自分の影ひとつ
the only thing following me is my own shadow.
凍りついた道を 花の雨で埋めて
Fill the frozen path with a rain of flowers,
迷わないようにちゃんと教えてね
and teach me properly so I won't get lost.
奇跡だけで出来た完全結晶はない
There is no perfect crystal made solely by miracles,
だからそうひとつずつゆっくりと手をつないでいくの
That's why slowly, one by one, we hold hands and go on.
胸に張り付いたガラス 融けて流れる
The glass clinging to my chest melts and flows away,
光あふれる世界 もうすぐ
Into a world overflowing with light, very soon.
ひとりで守っていた 小さなあの部屋は
That small room I protected all by myself
少しだけ空いている場所があって
has a little space open,
ずっと知らなかったんだ ふたりでもいいんだって わからずに待っていた
I never knew, I waited without realizing that being two was fine too.
あの日はもう
That day is already...
雪解けと一緒に 春にかわっていくよ
Changing into spring along with the melting snow.
透明な水になって そしてね
Becoming clear water, and then,
アザレアを咲かすよ 長い冬の後に
I'll make azaleas bloom after the long winter.
何度でも 何度でも 陽の満ちるこの部屋の中で
Over and over again, in this sunlit room.
の、雪ときーでした！みんなどう？
It's "Yuki-toki"! How is it, everyone?
雪ときは初挑戦なんですけど
It's my first time trying "Yuki-toki", but...
いい感じ？
How does it feel?
ちょっと、これ以外のほしい、文字のコメントがほしい
I want comments using letters other than this!
最高！やった！
"Awesome!" Yay!
えー、やったぜ！ナイスだね！
Yay, I did it! Nice!
ああ、最高すぎた！よかった！
Ah, it was too awesome! I'm glad!
春物好きだからさ、その、なんか逆の魔女っていうか、そっちもいいなと思ってやってみたいと思ってました！
I like spring items, so like, the opposite of a witch, I thought that'd be nice too and wanted to try it!
さあ、次はですね、あれをやっていきたいと思います！
Now, next up, I'd like to do that thing!
さっきのね、これね、ねねの記憶力が試されるんですけど、みんなも覚えてる？ねねが間違ってるかどう判断できるのは、みんなの記憶次第だからね！
The one from earlier, right? This tests Nene's memory, but do you all remember? Whether Nene is making a mistake depends on everyone's memory!
というわけで、うーん、ちょっと待てよ、
That being said... um, wait a second,
ええと、ここ、ここ何だっけ？ちょっと、うちにする間の全然、
um, where was this again? Um... wait, no problem during the turns,
全然、こうで、ふうふうして、ふうふう、回って、あ、はいはい、おっけおっけおっけ、
like this, breathing out, turning around, oh right right, okay okay okay,
うん、たぶんおっけ！いやーし！
yeah, probably okay! Awesome!
ほんな、やってみましょうか！え、行きます、
Alrighty, then, let's try it! Um, here we go,
ラブ ディズニー！
Love Destiny!
アイタイ アイアイアイアイノニ アエナイ
I want to see you, love, love, love, love, love,
アイアイアイアイアイ 今夜は
but I can't meet you, love, love, love, tonight...
窓を打つ雨より 激しい嵐に揺れてる
Shaken by a storm more fierce than the rain beating against the window.
アエナイ アイアイアイアイアイ から
Since I can't meet you, love, love, love, love, love,
もっと愛 Love Love つのるよ
my love just grows stronger and stronger.
燃え尽きてもいい これが
It's okay if I burn out to ashes,
最後の真実
this is the ultimate truth.
初めての出会いは 平凡だったけど
Our first meeting was ordinary, but...
会う度に過去の 誰よりも惹かれてく
Every time we meet, I'm drawn to you more than anyone from the past.
こんな気持ちの訳 うまく言えないけど
I can't quite put this feeling into words, but...
運命の恋と 人は呼ぶのでしょう
People would probably call this a fated love.
ひとみ閉じてたら ふたりになれる
When I close my eyes, we can be together.
今 たとえ この部屋ひとりでも
Now, even if I'm all alone in this room,
It's my only destiny
アイタイ アイアイアイアイノニ アエナイ
I want to see you, love, love, love, love, love,
アイアイアイアイアイ 今夜は
but I can't meet you, love, love, love, tonight...
勝手にあふれてく 激情を止められない
I can't stop these overflowing, passionate emotions.
だから アイタイ アイアイアイアイノニ アエナイ
That's why, I want to see you, love, love, love, love, love,
アイアイアイアイアイ
but I can't meet you, love, love, love...
もう戻れはしない これが
There's no turning back now,
最後の真実
this is the ultimate truth.
誰かを思う時 苦しくなるなんてね
Loving someone can be so painful, can't it?
これまでの自分が 次々に崩れてく
My old self is crumbling away piece by piece.
ポーズとは裏腹 巻き込まれてゆく感じ
Contrary to my pose, I feel myself getting sucked in.
見えない力で 引き寄せられてゆく
Drawn closer by an unseen force.
ひとみそらさず ふたりになれた
Without looking away, we were able to be together.
あの夜の 鼓動忘れない
I'll never forget the heartbeat of that night.
It's my last destiny
アイタイ アイアイアイアイノニ アエナイ
I want to see you, love, love, love, love, love,
アイアイアイアイアイ 今夜は
but I can't meet you, love, love, love, tonight...
窓を打つ雨より 激しい嵐に揺れてる
Shaken by a storm more fierce than the rain beating against the window.
アエナイ アイアイアイアイアイ から
Since I can't meet you, love, love, love, love, love,
もっと愛 Love Love つのるよ
my love just grows stronger and stronger.
燃え尽きてもいい これが
It's okay if I burn out to ashes,
最後の真実
this is the ultimate truth.
ねえ 不思議 彼を想って泣ける
Hey, it's strange how I can cry just thinking about him.
夜があるって まるで Love Song
Having nights like this is just like a love song.
だから Love Love Love アイタイ
That's why I want to see you, Love, Love, Love
だけど Love Love Love 会えない
But I can't meet you, Love, Love, Love
もう戻れはしない
There's no turning back now
これが最後の真実
This is the final truth
来て！毎度先生ー！
Come on in, Maidon-sensei!
何点？100点満点中なら？
How many points? Out of 100?
可愛いから100点！
100 points because it's cute!
まいどん先生でしたー！
That was Maidon-sensei!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
イェーイ！見て、みんな！
Yeah! Look, everyone!
ブライトの新衣装になります！
This is our brand-new Bright outfit!
ここからステージがあって進んでいきたいと思います！
Let's head forward along the stage here!
一番の宝物！
My most precious treasure!
裾が濡れたなら
If my sleeves are wet,
乾くのを待てばいい
I should just wait for them to dry.
水音をたてて跳ねた
Splashing water, I jumped.
きみが教えてくれたんだ もう恐くない
You taught me, I'm not scared anymore.
握っていてくれた この手を離さなきゃだめだ
I have to let go of this hand you held for me.
ひとりでもゆくよ 例え辛くても
I'll go on alone, even if it's painful.
みんなで見た夢は 必ず持ってくよ
I'll definitely take the dream we saw together.
みんなとがいいな みんなとがよかった
I wanted to be with everyone, I'm glad it was with everyone.
でも目覚めた朝 誰も居ないんだね
But on the morning I woke up, no one is there.
もう振り返っても
Even if I look back now...
もう 振り返っても 誰の影もない
Even if I look back, there's no one's shadow
水たまりだけが 光った
Only the puddles were shining
生きてくこと それは
Living life...
立ち向かっていくこと
is facing forward and confronting things.
それがわかったなら
Once I understood that,
後は踏み出す勇気だけ
all that's left is the courage to take a step forward.
どこまでもゆくよ ここで知ったこと
I'll go anywhere, what I learned here
幸せという夢を 叶えてみせるよ
I'll make the dream called happiness come true.
みんなと離れても どんなに遠くなっても
Even if I'm separated from everyone, no matter how far away I get,
新しい朝に この僕は生きるよ
I will live on this new morning.
ひとりでもゆくよ 死にたくなっても
I'll go alone, even if I want to die
声が聞こえるよ 死ではいけないと
I can hear a voice saying you mustn't die
例え辛くても 闇に閉ざされても
Even if it's painful, even if I'm shut away in darkness
心の奥には 明かりが灯ってるよ
There is a light shining deep in my heart
巡って流れて 時は移ろいだが
Revolving and flowing, time shifted away
もう何があったか 思い出せないけど
I can't remember what happened anymore, but
目を閉じてみれば みんなの笑い声
If I close my eyes, everyone's laughter
なぜかそれが今 一番の宝物
For some reason, that is my most precious treasure now
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
どーん！
Boom!
え、も、え、も、えろいねー！
So emotional, so emotional, so emotional!
というわけで、ここでみんなのテンションぶち上がりのところで、えー、まだラスト一曲あるんですけど、その前にグッズの紹介させてくなーさーい！こっちな！
And so, right when everyone's energy is peaking... Um, we still have one last song, but before that, let me introduce the merchandise! This way!
えー、ももすずねね誕生日記念2023のグッズが出まーす！いぇーい！こっちな！
Um, Momosuzu Nene's 2023 Birthday Commemorative merchandise is coming out! Yay! This way!
ととーん！アクリルジオラマスタンド、ランダムアクリルキーホルダー、ねねぬいくるみ、そして記念ASMRボイス2種類、これー、あまあまとからからの2種類のASMRー！
Ta-da! Acrylic diorama stand, random acrylic keychain, Nene plushie, and commemorative ASMR voice 2-types, this—, two types of ASMR, sweet and spicy!
があります。そして、特典のポストカードを
There is. And the bonus postcards
1つずつ見ていきましょう！
let's check them one by one!
こちら、
Here,
蟹ビーム先生に描いていただきました、
illustrated by Kani Biimu-sensei,
アクリルジオラママスタンド！
the acrylic diorama stand!
イェーイ！ なんかパーティ風でなんか、
Yay! It's kind of party-themed,
すごいかわいい感じでしょう？
and super cute, right?
これちょっと、えー、ラスト曲の匂わせで、
This is a little hint at the final song...
ジャズジャック先生に描いていただきました、
Illustrated by JAZZ JACK-sensei,
ランダムのアクリルキーホルダーになります！
these are random acrylic keyholders!
かわいい！見てみて！いろんな表情で描いていただきました！
Cute! Look at this! Drawn with various expressions!
チェーンの部分も桃になっててかわいいのでぜひチェックしてください！
The chain is shaped like a peach, so please check it out!
そしてこちら、
And here,
ももすずねねのぬいぐるみです！
is the Momosuzu Nene plushie!
ホロライブ公式でもぬいぐるみ出てますが、それとは別に人形が出てます！
Official Hololive ones exist, but this is a separate plushie!
こちらはアウターの着脱が可能になってますので、
You can put on and take off the outer jacket,
脱がせたり着せたり、そんなことをしながら、
so while dressing and undressing it,
みんなのお好みのよにカスタムして、次のライブとかあったら振ってほしいなと思います！
you can customize it and wave it at future lives!
そして、
And,
フルセットを購入してくれた人には、なんと久しぶりの直筆サイン！
for full set buyers, a rare handwritten signature!
箔押しの複製メッセージのポストカードをプレゼント、じゃなくて付けさせていただきます！
Plus a postcard with a foil-stamped duplicate message!
ねねが真心込めて1枚1枚書きますので、よかったらチェックよろしくお願いします！
Nene will heart-feltingly write each one, so please check it out!
さて、次で最後の曲になるんですけれども、
Now, the next song will be the final one,
次は、新曲です！
and it's a new song!
めっちゃ楽しい感じでわくわくでルンルンな感じの曲ですので、
It's a super fun, exciting, and upbeat song,
みんなに楽しんでもらえたらなと思います！
so I hope everyone enjoys it!
それでは、聞いてください。
So please listen to it.
コングラチュマッチ！
Congratu-match!
あ～ぁ朝、目が覚めたら
Ah~ When morning comes and I wake up,
枕の側に帯付きの5000兆添えてあったらいいな
I wish 5,000 trillion yen was by my pillow!
あ～ぁ3食昼寝ありできることなら
Ah~ Three meals and naps, if possible,
おやつ付き大企業コングラッチCHU☆社長出勤
with snacks, big company, Congratu CHU☆ arrival!
全体祝いえ！
Celebrate everyone!
生まれてできた今日に
To today when I was born,
おめでとうっ！
Congratulations!
今日、明日、明後日
Today, tomorrow, the day after tomorrow,
毎日誰かの誕生日祝福の鈴鳴らしたら
every day is someone's birthday, ring the bell of blessing,
笑顔咲けっ！
and smiles will bloom!
月曜はおやすみ
Mondays are for resting,
水曜もなしで
Wednesdays without work either,
不労所得毎日ボーナス～
unearned income, daily bonuses~
そうだ！明日も何かの休日にしようそうしよう
That's right! Let's make tomorrow a holiday too!
異世界からやってきた
Coming from another world,
憧れと希望を胸にこの場所
longing and hope in my chest, to this place,
歌って踊って全世界届けましょう届けましょう
singing and dancing, let's deliver it to the world!
あ～ぁ朝、起きるだけで褒められたいな
Ah~ I want praise just for waking up in the morning!
誰にも見せてない才能そろそろ出してやるか
Time to show off talent no one's seen yet!
あ～多分いる神様聞こえてますか？
Ah~ Are you listening, God, if you're out there?
願ってるこの願いすべてを叶えてくれー！
Please make this wish I'm praying for come true!
全体祝いえ！
Celebrate everyone!
おれはこの歌ってことでいいよねありがとう！
This song is fine as the ending, right? Thank you!
あ～あ 朝、目が覚めたら
Ah, if when I woke up in the morning,
枕の側に帯付きの5000兆添えられてたらいいな
5 trillion yen with a band was right by my pillow...
生まれてきた今日に おめでとうっ！
Happy birthday to the day I was born!
今日、明日、明後日 毎日誰かの誕生日
Today, tomorrow, the day after—every day is someone's birthday.
祝福の鈴鳴らしたら 笑顔咲ケ！
Ring the bells of blessing and let smiles bloom!
ロケットを作って どこまでもいこう
Let's build a rocket and go anywhere,
宇宙旅行 月すら超えて
on a space journey, far beyond even the moon!
そうだ！明日も 誰かのお祝いをしよう！そうしようっ！
That's right! Let's celebrate someone tomorrow too! Let's do it!
みんなみんな おめでとうっ！
Congratulations to everyone, everyone!
ありがとうございました！新曲「コングラCHU☆マーチ」でしたー！
Thank you very much! That was our new song, "CongratuCHU☆March"!
いかがでしたか？かわいいっしょ？
How was it? Pretty cute, right?
えーそして、えーこのあとは21時15分くらいから
And um, after this, around 9:15 PM,
えー、この曲のですね、あのMVが、あの発表になります！後ろがね、こんな感じで可愛い感じになってるので一緒に見に行きましょう！
um, the MV for this song will be released! The background looks all cute like this, so let's go check it out together!
これ見て、作ってもらったー！
Look at this, they made this for me!
えーそして、えーそのあと21時半くらいからは、メンバーシップ限定で、えーお疲れ様のアンコール会、そしてブライト衣装をじっくり舐め回す会を行いますので、よかったら見に来てください！
And um, after that, around 9:30 PM, we'll be holding a membership-only encore appreciation party and a session to thoroughly admire her bright outfit, so please come check it out if you'd like!
というわけでみんな、今日は最後まで見てくれてありがとーーー！
So everyone, thank you so much for watching all the way to the end today!
せーの、またねーーー！
Ready, set, see you later!